



7 Callander road, L6 8NT, Liverpool



+44 751 444 3025



www.noseyfish.co.uk



radoslav.tomas@noseyfish.co.uk

BIO

My name is **Radoslav Tomas** and I'm a web designer and developer. Originally from Slovakia, I currently live in Liverpool, UK. For almost eight years I have been working with data as an analyst for a company that monitors and analyses data from different media resources.

In 2011 I created <u>medan.sk</u> site where my colleagues and I promote our work and write short analyses about the latest topics. Currently, the site has more than 900 likes on Facebook (which is quite good for Slovak environment and can be compared with the most NGO's there) and serves as an inspiration for many Slovak journalists in their work.

This project has kindled my passion to become a web developer and one year ago I've started to build my first sites.

Since then I haven't stop coding...

KEY SKILLS AND TOOLS

HTML 5 (advanced)
CSS 3 (advanced)
jQuery (intermediate)
Python (basic to moderate)
MySQL (basic to moderate)
WordPress (basic)

Radoslav Tomas

Web developer and designer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst - Newton Media

February 2009 - present

I monitor and analyse data from different media sources (including social media) for a range of companies (banks, carmakers, pharmaceutical companies, council departments etc.). My work is to search for the data, collect, clean and filter it out. I produce media coverage reports (positive or negative articles, main topics, top media etc.) or inputs for marketers (advertising value equivalent, most influential authors etc.). In 2011 I created medan.sk site where my colleagues and I promote our work and write short analyses about the latest topics. Currently, the site has more than 900 likes on Facebook.

Care and support worker - L'Arche Liverpool

March 2013 - present

I support people with learning disabilities in order to assist them in the development of their independent living skills. This work has helped me to become fluent in English.

Editor - Jaga Group Publishing House

April 2008 - February 2009

Writing and editing on-line contents for company's site.

EDUCATION

Personal professional development

2014 - now

- learn2code.sk WebRebel 1 HTML, CSS and JavaScript (Certified course by the Ministry of Education in Slovak Republic)
- Coursera Webdesign For Everybody (5-part course), Programming For Everybody (Starting With Python), Python Data Structures, Using Databases With Python, Using Python To Access Web Data)
- Udemy The Complete Webdeveloper Course, SQL For Newbs Masterclass, Python Programming

Comenius University, Bratislava, Slovakia - MA in Journalism

2006 - 2008

Modules included - Digital skills for journalists, Web design in on-line journalism, Data processing

Comenius University, Bratislava, Slovakia - Bc in Marketing and PR

Modules included - Digital marketing strategies, Marketing and PR in the creative industries, Research methods

INTERESTS

Running

I have started to run two years ago, now I am training with some of my friends for the half-marathon in Bratislava in April 2017.

Creative writing

I have published <u>three collections</u> of poetry, which gained several prizes. I also took part in many poetry readings in Slovakia and abroad.